# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello, everyone. I'm Wang Gang.
# 本期视频我跟大家分享一道家常菜
In this video I'm going to share a homestyle dish with you.
# 电饭锅烧鸡腿
Rice Cooker Braised Chicken Leg
# 首先我们准备鸡腿一只
First we'll prepare a chicken leg.
# 剁掉鸡脚之后在大腿内侧划一刀
After chopping off the chicken feet, make a cut on the inside of the thigh.
# 划好之后在关节处转一圈切断脚筋
After you've cut on the thigh, turn around at the joint and cut off the hamstring.
# 然后用小刀将鸡腿肉剔除下来取出骨头
Then use a paring knife to remove the meat from the bones.
# 嫌麻烦的同学可以直接让摊主帮忙处理
Who couldn't do it you can ask the butcher to help you out.
# 下一步开始处理鸡腿肉
Start treating the chicken thigh next.
# 首先我们在鸡腿肉厚的地方切上几刀
First you cut a few cuts into the thick part of the chicken thigh.
# 这样方便腌制的时候入味和均匀受热
This help the flavor into meat and even heating.
# 然后再用刀背横竖地均匀敲打
Then, with the back of the knife, beat evenly across.
# 这一步的目的是将肉敲松散
The goal of this step is to break the meat loose.
# 然后再翻过来用刀角均匀的将筋膜切断
Then turn it over and cut the fascia evenly with the corner of the knife.
# 下一步开始腌制
Next, start marinating.
# 首先我们用适量的黄酒均匀地涂抹在鸡腿肉上面
First use some huangjiu rice wine to evenly coat the chicken thighs.
# 没有黄酒的同学也可以用料酒代替
If you don't have any huangjiu rice wine, you can use Chinese cooking wine instead.
# 然后撒上适量的黑胡椒面
Then sprinkle with a generous amount of black pepper
# 同学们黑胡椒最好现磨这样更香
Guys, it's better to grind the black pepper fresh. It's more delicious.
# 不喜欢胡椒味的同学也可以用姜葱末代替
For those of you who don't like the pepper flavor, you can also use minced ginger and onion instead.
# 最后撒上适量的土豆淀粉均匀腌制30分钟备用
Sprinkle with potato starch and marinate evenly for 30 minutes.
# 下一步开始准备料汁
Next, start preparing the sauce.
# 锅中加入香菜籽1小把（约10克）
Add 1 small handful of coriander seeds (about 10 grams) to the pot
# 加入干姜1小块
Add 1 small piece of dried ginger
# 加入良姜1小块
Add 1 small piece of galangal
# 加入黄姜1小块
Add 1 small piece of turmeric
# 加入少许千里香
Add a dash of thyme
# 加入荜拨1根
Adding 1pc of long pepper
# 加入少许小茴香
Add a dash of fennel seed
# 加入半颗八角
Add a half star anise.
# 加入适量的大葱段
Add some spring onions
# 最后加入适量的清水将香料煮10分钟
Finally, add some water to the spices and cook for 10 minutes.
# 找不齐香料的同学可以用香菜、生姜、八角、小茴香、大葱即可
If you can't find all the spices, you can use coriander, ginger, star anise, fennel seed and spring onion.
# 下一步我们开始调酱料（2份量）
Next let's started mixing the sauce (2 servings)
# 碗中加入适量的生抽酱油（20克）
Add some light soy sauce to the bowl (20g)
# 加入黄酒20克
Add 20g of huangjiu rice wine
# 加入排骨酱1勺（约4克）
Add 1 scoop of the rib sauce (about 4 grams)
# 加入海鲜酱1勺（约4克）
Add 1 spoonful of hoisin sauce (about 4 grams)
# 加入蚝油5克
Add 5 grams of oyster sauce
# 加入白糖2勺搅拌均匀备用
Add 2 teaspoons of sugar and mix well.
# 搅拌均匀之后再倒入煮好的香料水
Stir well before pouring in the cooked spice water.
# 最后加入1勺红曲米粉拌匀
Finally, add 1 spoonful of red yeast rice flour and mix well.
# 下一步开始制作
Start cooking next.
# 准备大葱2根切成小段备用
Prepare 2 large spring onions cut into short segments.
# 电饭锅烧热之后加入适量的油
Once the rice cooker is hot, add some oil.
# 同学们油可以适量的没过电饭锅凸起的部分
The oil need to go over the raised part of the rice cooker.
# 多放点油是为了防止锅底干烧
The extra oil is to prevent drying out.
# 油温5成热后加入适量的大葱段煎香
When the oil is 50 percent hot(150 ℃), add the spring onions and fry them.
# 大葱煎香之后捡出不用
After frying the spring onions, pick them out.
# 然后将腌制好的鸡腿肉皮朝下煎制3分钟
Then brown the marinated chicken thighs skin side down for 3 minutes
# 3分钟之后将鸡腿肉翻过来煎1分钟
After 3 minutes, flip the chicken thighs over and brown for 1 minute.
# 同学们注意煎这一面的时候鸡肉会粘锅
This side of the the chicken is easy to stick to the cooker.
# 是属于正常现象
It's normal.
# 粘锅的时候可以不用着急翻面
You don't have to rush to turn the chicken over when it sticks.
# 1分钟之后将锅中多余的油倒出
Pour out excess oil from the cooker after 1 minute
# 再加入适量的料汁
Then add some of the sauce.
# 然后盖上锅盖烧3分钟
Then cover the cooker and cook for 3 minutes.
# 同学们这个过程中粘锅的部分会自动脱落
The sticky part of the chicken will come off automatically in this process.
# 3分钟之后翻过来皮朝下开始收汁
After 3 minutes, turn it over, skin side down, and start reducing the sauce.
# 由于鸡皮这一面有较多的淀粉
Because there is more starch on this side of the chicken skin.
# 所以在煮（收汁）的时候必须经常推动
That's why you must always push while boiling!
# 这样可以防止粘底烧糊
This will prevent the chicken from sticking to the bottom.
# 当汤汁收浓之后即可捞出切片摆盘
When the sauce has thickened, remove chicken from the cooker and cut into slices.
# 最后再淋上剩余的汁水即可上菜
Top with the remaining sauce and serve.
# 一道非常简单美味的红烧鸡腿肉就制作完成
A very simple and delicious braised chicken thigh is ready!
# 下面开始技术总结
Let's start the technical summary.
# 第一 鸡肉最好选择新鲜紧实的黑脚鸡
First, the best chicken is fresh, firm and free range.
# 冻鸡腿次之
Frozen chicken leg is not as good, but also do the job.
# 不喜欢鸡腿的同学也可以选择鸡翅 鸡脯肉
For those of you who don't like chicken legs, chicken wings and breasts are also good options.
# 第二 如果选用新鲜的鸡腿肉
Second, if you use fresh chicken thighs.
# 必须经过刀背敲打和斩断筋膜
You need to beat the thigh with back of the knife and the fascia needs to be cut.
# 否则筋膜不断口感韧劲很强之外还会变形缩水严重
If not, the fascia will create tough texture, also the meat will deform dramatically.
# 第三 此菜比较适合非明火的电饭锅操作
Third, this dish is more suitable for non-flame rice cooker operation.
# 也可以用不粘锅制作
It can also be made in a non-sticky pan.
# 红烧鸡腿肉的技术总结完毕
End of technique summary for braised chicken thighs